<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<itemrelease version="2.0">
  <passage id="3710" version="5" bankkey="187">
    <attriblist>
      <attrib attid="stm_pass_id">
        <name>Stim: ITS ID</name>
        <val>3710</val>
        <desc>
        </desc>
      </attrib>
      <attrib attid="stm_pass_subject">
        <name>Stim: Subject</name>
        <val>ELA</val>
        <desc>
        </desc>
      </attrib>
      <attrib attid="stm_pass_desc">
        <name>Stim: Description</name>
        <val>5978 - SBAC_Field</val>
        <desc>
        </desc>
      </attrib>
    </attriblist>
    <resourceslist>
      <resource type="wordList" id="1759" index="1" bankkey="187" />
    </resourceslist>
    <content language="ENU" version="2.0" approvedVersion="5">
      <title><![CDATA[&#xA0;]]></title>
      <author><![CDATA[&#xA0;]]></author>
      <stem><![CDATA[<p style="font-weight:bold; ">On a <span id="passage_3710_TAG_1_BEGIN">Mission</span></p><p style="font-weight:bold; ">&#xA0;</p><p style="">It was out of the ordinary for Lefty to be late. Clark Smyth, the stationmaster for the Pony Express station, was becoming concerned. Mr. Smyth added a few pieces of wood to the cookstove. He was trying to keep the food he had prepared for Lefty warm. As the hours passed and the fire in the cookstove lost strength, the sound of <span id="passage_3710_TAG_4" class="its-tag" data-tag="word" data-tag-boundary="start" data-word-index="1"></span>hooves<span class="its-tag" data-tag-ref="passage_3710_TAG_4" data-tag-boundary="end"></span> could be heard in the darkness of the valley.</p><p style="">&#xA0;</p><p style="">Once the distinct sound of hooves was heard near the station, Mr. Smyth leaped into the air and dropped a big wooden ladle into the cooking pot. He ran outside to greet the rider. I followed closely behind Mr. Smyth, eager to see my friend, Lefty Trotter, a Pony Express rider. In the moonlight, Mr. Smyth and I could barely notice the horse approaching.</p><p style="">&#xA0;</p><p style="">When the horse approached the station, it was easy to see that something was terribly wrong. The horse was not carrying a rider. Lefty was nowhere in sight.</p><p style="">&#xA0;</p><p style="">The horse that stopped in front of the station was coated in sweat and looked exhausted after traveling from Warm Springs station. Mr. Smyth walked the horse over to the watering trough while I gathered some oats and hay. After the horse was tied to the hitching post, Mr. Smyth removed the mochila, a leather saddle covered with four cantinas, or pockets, containing mail that needed to be delivered to California.</p><p style="">&#xA0;</p><p style="">"We need to find Lefty," Mr. Smyth said.</p><p style="">&#xA0;</p><p style="">"Yes, sir," I answered, "but the mail has to arrive at the correct <span id="passage_3710_TAG_5" class="its-tag" data-tag="word" data-tag-boundary="start" data-word-index="2"></span>destination<span class="its-tag" data-tag-ref="passage_3710_TAG_5" data-tag-boundary="end"></span>, and I intend to deliver it."</p><p style="">&#xA0;</p><p style="">"Oh, no you don't," Mr. Smyth shook his head as he brushed the horse. "You are not experienced and do not know the trail. It's too dangerous out there at night when you are unfamiliar with the <span id="passage_3710_TAG_6" class="its-tag" data-tag="word" data-tag-boundary="start" data-word-index="3"></span>route<span class="its-tag" data-tag-ref="passage_3710_TAG_6" data-tag-boundary="end"></span>."</p><p style="">&#xA0;</p><p style="">"Look, Mr. Smyth," I said, "you know that Mr. Lincoln was just elected President of the United States. We don't know what important news is in this mochila, and I am the only one here who can get it delivered on time."</p><p style="">&#xA0;</p><p style="">"But over the mountains and through rugged territory is no place for someone with your experience."</p><p style="">&#xA0;</p><p style="">"Our orders are to deliver the mail on time, regardless of what has happened to Lefty. There's no time for arguing, Mr. Smyth; we have to follow the schedule."</p><p style="">&#xA0;</p><p style="">Mr. Smyth nodded his head in agreement. I ran inside the wooden shelter and quickly ate a few spoonfuls of beans and pieces of bacon before coming back outside to mount the horse for the journey. I waved my hat at Mr. Smyth before the station disappeared into the dry, dusty distance. The darkness of the night did not allow Mr. Smyth or me to notice the storm clouds in the sky.</p><p style="">&#xA0;</p><p style="">Though I did not know the entire route, I did know that the next station was 12 miles to the west, about as far as Buddy could <span id="passage_3710_TAG_7" class="its-tag" data-tag="word" data-tag-boundary="start" data-word-index="4"></span>gallop<span class="its-tag" data-tag-ref="passage_3710_TAG_7" data-tag-boundary="end"></span> without resting. The trail I traveled was one of the passages along the entire route of the Pony <span id="passage_3710_TAG_2_BEGIN">Express-St.</span> Joseph, Missouri, to Sacramento, California. Stations were established every 10 to 15 miles or so to give riders food, water, and a rested horse. Most Pony Express riders used anywhere from six to eight different horses and covered from 75 to 100 miles before their work was done.</p><p style="">&#xA0;</p><p style="">It started to storm about eight miles west of Rocky Ridge station. Rock Creek station, my first stop, was far ahead. The wind created cold, stinging rain in the valleys. Still, there was no stopping and no waiting for the storm to pass. The mail had to be on time. I put my head alongside Buddy's neck as we pushed through the dark and cold rain.</p><p style="">&#xA0;</p><p style="">As wind and rain grew in intensity, the trail carried us to higher altitudes and along a narrow mountain ridge that was covered with flat, slippery rocks. Rain turned into sleet and then snow. I dismounted and led Buddy nervously along the ridgeline of the mountain, trying to maintain control.</p><p style="">&#xA0;</p><p style="">After a miserable hour that seemed to never end, Buddy and I began a slow descent into a valley. Although a storm has passed, a blanket of snow covered the countryside, making it impossible to follow the trail. Without hesitation, I galloped Buddy westward hoping to find the trail or someone who could guide us to it. Eventually, we came to a creek that flowed through the valley. It was too wide, too fast, and too deep. But there was no time to waste. We followed the course of the creek north until we came upon a shallow area.</p><p style="">&#xA0;</p><p style="">I stood tall in the saddle in order to <span id="passage_3710_TAG_8" class="its-tag" data-tag="word" data-tag-boundary="start" data-word-index="5"></span>get my bearings<span class="its-tag" data-tag-ref="passage_3710_TAG_8" data-tag-boundary="end"></span>. Luck was with us, and I located the trail just to the north. As Buddy covered the remaining miles to the station, I thought about the challenges I had overcome on this journey. When the Rocky Creek station came into sight, Buddy kicked up her heels and stormed toward the food, water and rest.</p><p style="">&#xA0;</p><p style="">A stationmaster met us outside the corral. As I climbed out of the saddle, Buddy chuffed, sides heaving, from the long ride. The man moved the mochila with its soggy mail and placed it on the saddle of a fresh horse without saying a word. I ate a mouthful of beans and bacon before climbing into the saddle of a rested horse. As I started to leave, I heard the stationmaster ask, "Where's Lefty?"</p>]]></stem>
      <attachmentlist>
        <attachment id="braillefile1" type="BRF" subtype="contracted" file="passage_3710_enu_contracted.brf" />
        <attachment id="braillefile2" type="BRF" subtype="uncontracted" file="passage_3710_enu_uncontracted.brf" />
      </attachmentlist>
      <apipAccessibility>
        <accessibilityInfo>
          <accessElement identifier="ae1">
            <contentLinkInfo itsLinkIdentifierRef="passage_3710_TAG_1_BEGIN" type="Text">
              <objectLink />
            </contentLinkInfo>
            <relatedElementInfo>
              <readAloud>
                <textToSpeechPronunciation>Mission.</textToSpeechPronunciation>
                <textToSpeechPronunciationAlternate>Mission.</textToSpeechPronunciationAlternate>
              </readAloud>
              <brailleText>
                <brailleTextString>Mission</brailleTextString>
              </brailleText>
            </relatedElementInfo>
          </accessElement>
          <accessElement identifier="ae6">
            <contentLinkInfo itsLinkIdentifierRef="passage_3710_TAG_2_BEGIN" type="Text">
              <objectLink />
            </contentLinkInfo>
            <relatedElementInfo>
              <readAloud>
                <textToSpeechPronunciation>Express Saint</textToSpeechPronunciation>
                <textToSpeechPronunciationAlternate>Express Saint</textToSpeechPronunciationAlternate>
              </readAloud>
              <brailleText>
                <brailleTextString>Express-St.</brailleTextString>
              </brailleText>
            </relatedElementInfo>
          </accessElement>
        </accessibilityInfo>
      </apipAccessibility>
    </content>
  </passage>
</itemrelease>